Translation and timing: Maram
الترجمة والتوقيت: مرام
I've always been like this
لطالما كنت هكذا
When I make up my mind to do something
عندما أحسم أمري أن أفعل شيئًا
I do it no matter what
أنا أفعلها مهما كان الأمر
- the second episode -
- الحلقة الثانية -
I'll take one of these
سآخذ واحدة من هؤلاء
wait a moment
انتظر لحظة
Don't go, stay five minutes longer
لا تذهب ، ابق خمس دقائق أطول
Wait, I'll cook you something delicious
انتظر ، سأطبخ لك شيئًا لذيذًا
something delicious?
شيء لذيذ؟
(22 missed calls from Miss Kim) (7 unread messages)
(22 مكالمة فائتة من Miss Kim) (7 رسائل غير مقروءة)
(Deleted)
(تم الحذف)
(J. Owen Sandby)
(جيه أوين ساندبي)
Welcome
أهلا وسهلا
Isn't this Ji Won's phone?
أليس هاتف جي وون هذا؟
That's right who is with me?
هذا صحيح من معي؟
This is my daily
هذا هو يومي
daily?
اليومي؟
Yes, my day
نعم يومي
this means
هذا يعنى
That you were in America all that time?
هل كنت في أمريكا كل ذلك الوقت؟
Yes, I went to university there
نعم ، ذهبت إلى الجامعة هناك
So, are you back forever now?
لذا ، هل عدت إلى الأبد الآن؟
Yes
نعم
I'm totally back
لقد عدت تماما
I'm back already but I don't know what to start with
لقد عدت بالفعل ولكني لا أعرف ما الذي أبدأ به
But, even I don't know what to do
لكن حتى أنا لا أعرف ماذا أفعل
I wasn't accepted in any of the places I wanted
لم يتم قبولي في أي من الأماكن التي أردت
And the place I work at is very small
والمكان الذي أعمل فيه صغير جدًا
With that, you became a journalist as you wanted
وبذلك أصبحت صحفيًا كما تريد
Honestly, I hated my company a lot at first
بصراحة ، كرهت شركتي كثيرًا في البداية
But it doesn't matter how I got here
لكن لا يهم كيف وصلت إلى هنا
What am I going to do in the future? This is the real problem
ماذا سأفعل في المستقبل؟  هذه هي المشكلة الحقيقية
So, what kind of work do you want to do?
إذن ، ما نوع العمل الذي تريد القيام به؟
I have a lot of relationships I work for the alumni association now
لدي الكثير من العلاقات التي أعمل بها في جمعية الخريجين الآن
No, I didn't call you to ask for a favor
لا ، لم أتصل بك لأطلب معروفًا
Do you want to teach children as part-time work?
هل ترغب في تعليم الأطفال كعمل بدوام جزئي؟
Someone with your qualifications will be fed up by people
شخص ما بمؤهلاتك سوف يضايقه الناس
What kind of business is this?
أي نوع من الأعمال هذا؟
I know someone who runs an art academy
أعرف شخصًا يدير أكاديمية للفنون
The academy is very big and famous
الأكاديمية كبيرة ومشهورة جدًا
You have a degree in arts, right?
لديك شهادة في الفنون ، أليس كذلك؟
me on March 29, 1981
لي في 29 مارس 1981
educational background
خلفية تعليمية
"It doesn't matter how I got here."
"لا يهم كيف وصلت إلى هنا."
What am I going to do in the future? This is the real problem
ماذا سأفعل في المستقبل؟  هذه هي المشكلة الحقيقية
Are you going somewhere today?
هل انت ذاهب الى مكان ما اليوم؟
I have an important meeting
لدي اجتماع مهم
Miss Anna
ملكة جمال آنا
Your educational background is excellent
خلفيتك التعليمية ممتازة
Usually, people like you don't come to work in academies
عادة ، لا يأتي الأشخاص مثلك للعمل في الأكاديميات
It hasn't been long since I got back from America
لم يمض وقت طويل منذ أن عدت من أمريكا
I felt like I had to do something
شعرت أنني يجب أن أفعل شيئًا ما
But I'm not used to the situation yet, and it's strange
لكني لست معتادًا على الموقف بعد ، وهو أمر غريب
Right, I heard a lot about you from Ji Won
حسنًا ، لقد سمعت الكثير عنك من جي وون
But I have no experience
لكن ليس لدي خبرة
You have received theoretical and practical training and even have a master's degree
لقد تلقيت تدريبًا نظريًا وعمليًا وحتى حصلت على درجة الماجستير
Your educational background is more than enough
خلفيتك التعليمية أكثر من كافية
To tell you the truth, the educational background of the lecturers is very important to us
لأقول لك الحقيقة ، الخلفية التعليمية للمحاضرين مهمة جدًا بالنسبة لنا
I trust you because Ji Won introduced me to you
أنا أثق بك لأن جي وون قدمني إليك
There are not many dedicated and hardworking people these days
لا يوجد الكثير من الناس المخلصين والعمل الدؤوبين هذه الأيام
When can you start working?
متى يمكنك أن تبدأ العمل؟
You have kept it well
لقد حافظت عليه بشكل جيد
Excuse me
اعذرني
Do you think I can sell this? It's an hour
هل تعتقد أنه يمكنني بيع هذا؟  إنها ساعة
?Vincent & Co
؟ فنسنت وشركاه
What's the matter?
ما الأمر؟
Did you buy it yourself?
هل اشتريتها بنفسك؟
No, I received it as a gift
لا ، لقد تلقيتها كهدية
In fact
في الواقع
This company was in the news 4 or 5 years ago due to fraud
كانت هذه الشركة في الأخبار منذ 4 أو 5 سنوات بسبب الاحتيال
Didn't you hear about it?
ألم تسمع عنها؟
It was made in China and only screw was added in Switzerland
تم صنعه في الصين وتم إضافة المسمار فقط في سويسرا
To say it was made there
لأقول أنه تم صنعه هناك
It cost 100,000 won but they sold it for 8 or 10 million won
تكلفتها 100000 وون لكنهم باعوها مقابل 8 أو 10 ملايين وون
If you just got it, who gave it to you, really bad person
إذا حصلت عليه للتو ، فمن أعطاك إياه ، شخص سيء حقًا
It's impossible he didn't know that
من المستحيل أنه لم يكن يعرف ذلك
(Seoul Family Court)
(محكمة الأسرة في سيول)
Yumi has been given permission to change her name to Anna.
حصلت Yumi على الإذن بتغيير اسمها إلى Anna.
Are you the one who called me earlier?
هل أنت من اتصل بي في وقت سابق؟
My little brother is planning to study abroad so I'm doing research
يخطط أخي الصغير للدراسة في الخارج لذلك أقوم بالبحث
Schools abroad are different from here, they are not about the best student
تختلف المدارس في الخارج عن هنا ، فهي لا تتعلق بأفضل طالب
It is better that he prepare diligently to study
والأفضل أن يستعد باجتهاد للدراسة
Techniques here have no value
التقنيات هنا ليس لها قيمة
Your written and artistic works should show emotion
يجب أن تظهر أعمالك المكتوبة والفنية المشاعر
Even if many people apply for the same specialty
حتى لو تقدم الكثير من الناس لنفس التخصص
They take into account...
يأخذون في الاعتبار ...
They take into account that everyone has their own path
يأخذون في الاعتبار أن لكل شخص طريقه الخاص
The most important thing is to work for a long time
أهم شيء هو العمل لفترة طويلة
The most important thing to work for a long time is
أهم شيء للعمل لفترة طويلة هو
to find
لايجاد
Finding a new perspective on your own
إيجاد منظور جديد بنفسك
This is what universities definitely want
هذا ما تريده الجامعات بالتأكيد
Teachers want to know the story behind your artwork
يريد المعلمون معرفة القصة وراء عملك الفني
I understand what you're saying
وأنا أفهم ما تقوله
But I don't know how to find a new perspective
لكني لا أعرف كيف أجد منظورًا جديدًا
It's okay, don't rush
لا بأس ، لا تتعجل
My English score hasn't improved even after a year
لم تتحسن درجتي في اللغة الإنجليزية حتى بعد عام
Ga In was accepted into CalArts after six months of preparation
تم قبول Ga In في CalArts بعد ستة أشهر من الإعداد
Did you want to get over it?
هل تريد تجاوزه؟
Honestly, she was just so lucky
بصراحة ، كانت محظوظة للغاية
It's not that good
هذا ليس جيدًا
نا راي
نا راي
When a person becomes unhappy
عندما يصبح الشخص غير سعيد
Begins to take an interest in the lives of others
يبدأ في الاهتمام بحياة الآخرين
I used to be miserable in the past because of some people
اعتدت أن أكون بائسة في الماضي بسبب بعض الناس
But now I'm just waiting for my chance and I don't believe in luck anymore
لكن الآن أنا فقط في انتظار فرصتي ولم أعد أؤمن بالحظ
Don't care about others
لا تهتم بالآخرين
Just think of yourself
فقط فكر في نفسك
You got a high score on the placement test
لقد حصلت على درجة عالية في اختبار تحديد المستوى
Have you ever taken English lessons?
هل سبق لك أن أخذت دروس اللغة الإنجليزية؟
No, it's my first time going to an English academy
لا ، إنها المرة الأولى التي أذهب فيها إلى أكاديمية اللغة الإنجليزية
I have taken the TOEIC test before and got around 900 points
لقد أجريت اختبار TOEIC من قبل وحصلت على حوالي 900 نقطة
This is a great grade
هذه درجة رائعة
People who have studied before can quickly catch up with others
يمكن للأشخاص الذين درسوا من قبل اللحاق بالآخرين بسرعة
I will prepare the registration form for you, please wait
سوف أقوم بإعداد استمارة التسجيل من أجلك ، يرجى الانتظار
My day I'm the aunt from the store next door
يومي أنا العمة من المتجر المجاور
Yes Aunt, did something happen?
نعم خالتي ، هل حدث شيء؟
Nothing big but you should come soon
لا شيء كبير ولكن يجب أن تأتي قريبا
The market area will undergo redevelopment
ستخضع منطقة السوق لإعادة التطوير
And you will get compensation for your sewing shop
وستحصل على تعويض لمحل الخياطة الخاص بك
redevelopment?
إعادة التطوير؟
Auntie you have arrived
لقد وصلت عمتي
Mom
أم
I came
انا قد جئت
You're late, right?
لقد تأخرت ، أليس كذلك؟
No Was the road busy?
لا هل كان الطريق مزدحما؟
No Are you okay?
لا هل انت بخير
Mom, I'm here
أمي ، أنا هنا
Hong Joo unnie, my day has arrived
هونغ جو أوني ، لقد وصل يومي
She can't hear very well lately and her memory comes and goes
لم تستطع السمع جيدًا مؤخرًا وذاكرتها تأتي وتذهب
Mom
أم
Do you miss me?
هل تفتقدنى؟
It will take you half an hour to get to know you
سوف يستغرق الأمر نصف ساعة للتعرف عليك
She will keep thinking and asking herself who you are
سوف تستمر في التفكير وتسأل نفسها من أنت
You said this place was going to be a train station, right?
قلت أن هذا المكان سيكون محطة قطار ، أليس كذلك؟
Yeah, do you know the road we used to use as a stop?
نعم ، هل تعرف الطريق الذي اعتدنا استخدامه كمحطة؟
They will build a decent train station there
سوف يبنون محطة قطار لائقة هناك
I brought you the documents from the union representative
أحضرت لك المستندات من ممثل النقابة
Have you thought about what I told you about?
هل فكرت في ما قلته لك؟
yes
نعم
Like I said
كما قلت
I think it's best to put her in a nursing home
أعتقد أنه من الأفضل وضعها في دار لرعاية المسنين
You did well to think
لقد أحسنت التفكير
If I take a second, she could end up in big trouble
إذا أخذت ثانية ، فقد ينتهي بها الأمر في ورطة كبيرة
with this money
بهذا المال
You can get a wonderful apartment for rent in Seoul
يمكنك الحصول على شقة رائعة للإيجار في سيول
is not it?
أليس كذلك؟
This is correct
هذا صحيح
Help yourself
ساعد نفسك
I didn't know you had a guest
لم أكن أعرف أن لديك ضيفًا
This is Professor Yoon Soo Young, don't you know her? She is an older classmate of yours
هذه البروفيسور يون سو يونغ ألا تعرفها؟  هي زميلتك الأكبر سنا
Sorry?
آسف؟
This is the lecture I told you about
هذه هي المحاضرة التي أخبرتك عنها
She probably doesn't know me
ربما لا تعرفني
Since I started school the year I graduated
منذ أن بدأت الدراسة في العام الذي تخرجت فيه
Sorry I didn't recognize you
آسف لم أتعرف عليك
No need to apologize, sit here
لا داعي للاعتذار ، اجلس هنا
have a seat
تفضل بالجلوس
I have a class to teach
لدي فصل للتدريس
Enjoy your talk
استمتع بكلامك
It's the first time I've seen her face
إنها المرة الأولى التي أرى فيها وجهها
But a lot of rumors spread about it among Korean students
لكن الكثير من الشائعات انتشرت حول هذا الموضوع بين الطلاب الكوريين
Rumors?
شائعات؟
It was very popular
كانت تحظى بشعبية كبيرة
I don't remember if it was Pyeongchang District or Seongbuk District
لا أتذكر ما إذا كانت منطقة بيونغتشانغ أو منطقة سيونغ بوك
In any case
على كل حال
It is said that she owns a lot of real estate
يقال إنها تمتلك الكثير من العقارات
I figured she's not from an ordinary family by looking at her clothes
اعتقدت أنها ليست من عائلة عادية بالنظر إلى ملابسها
She was accepted due to her family's donations and her testimony was managed with money
تم قبولها بسبب تبرعات عائلتها وتم تدبير شهادتها بالمال
She was a very popular party girl
كانت فتاة حفلات مشهورة جدًا
That's why many of her colleagues don't even know her face
لهذا السبب لا يعرف الكثير من زملائها وجهها
She didn't even go to reunions after she came back to Korea
لم تذهب حتى إلى لم الشمل بعد عودتها إلى كوريا
But she is very hardworking
لكنها تعمل بجد
It's very good
انها جيدة جدا
That's surprising
هذا مدهش
She has money and a good educational background. Why work here?
لديها مال وخلفية تعليمية جيدة.  لماذا العمل هنا؟
Oh, you came!
أوه ، لقد أتيت!
You can buy this for 90,000 won
يمكنك شراء هذا مقابل 90000 وون
I will give you a discount since you are a regular customer
سأقدم لك خصمًا لأنك عميل منتظم
Instead, don't you have a Chanel jacket this year?
بدلا من ذلك ، أليس لديك سترة شانيل هذا العام؟
Do you mean the plaid cloth? - Yes
هل تقصد القماش المنقوش؟  - نعم
This hasn't arrived yet. Come next week
هذا لم يصل بعد.  تعال الأسبوع المقبل
OK
نعم
Our Dior skirt is beautiful
تنورة ديور لدينا جميلة
look
نظرة
Is not she beautiful?
اليست جميلة؟
It will suit you well
سوف يناسبك جيدا
give it to me
اعطني اياه
- Teacher - Hello, Na Ray
- المعلم - مرحبا ، نا راي
Master, I have been accepted
سيدي ، لقد تم قبولي
I'm going to Yale University!
انا ذاهب الى جامعة ييل!
I just received an email
لقد تلقيت للتو بريدًا إلكترونيًا
truly?
حقا؟
I'm going to be your youngest classmate now!
سأكون أصغر زميل لك الآن!
OK
نعم
Congratulations to you Na Ray
مبروك لك نا راي
What should I do?
ماذا علي أن أفعل؟
I'm so happy I can't breathe
أنا سعيد للغاية لأنني لا أستطيع التنفس
I'll visit the academy later with my mom
سأزور الأكاديمية لاحقًا مع أمي
Good
جيد
Yale?
ييل؟
As for writing articles
أما بالنسبة لكتابة المقالات
Instead of trying your best to just write
بدلا من بذل قصارى جهدك للكتابة فقط
It's even better when someone talented writes it and makes it look fun and unpretentious
بل من الأفضل أن يكتبها شخص موهوب ويجعلها تبدو ممتعة وبسيطة
But if you try to add a lot of fun to it
ولكن إذا حاولت إضافة الكثير من المرح إليها
The article will start to lose its direction
ستبدأ المقالة في فقدان اتجاهها
If you overdo it to make it look too good it will distract the reader and become blurred
إذا بالغت في جعلها تبدو جيدة جدًا ، فإنها ستشتت انتباه القارئ وتصبح غير واضحة
Miss Lee, this is so hard
آنسة لي ، هذا صعب للغاية
You say it'll get boring if we try our best
أنت تقول إنها ستصبح مملة إذا بذلنا قصارى جهدنا
He is right
انه علي حق
Is this difficult?
هل هذا صعب؟
Then it doesn't have to be too much fun
ثم لا يجب أن يكون هناك الكثير من المرح
The most important thing is to know exactly what you want to talk about
أهم شيء هو أن تعرف بالضبط ما تريد التحدث عنه
As for your articles, I just changed the order
بالنسبة لمقالاتك ، لقد غيرت الترتيب للتو
What do you think of them after you changed the order? The goal is stronger than before
ما رأيك بهم بعد أن قمت بتغيير الترتيب؟  الهدف أقوى من ذي قبل
That's the parameter
هذه هي المعلمة
Can't we go eat something after we're done?
ألا يمكننا أن نأكل شيئًا بعد أن ننتهي؟
Buy us pizza
اشتري لنا بيتزا
Pizza! Pizza!
بيتزا!  بيتزا!
I have plans today I can't
لدي خطط اليوم لا أستطيع
What kind of plans?
أي نوع من الخطط؟
where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟
You have already arrived
لقد وصلت بالفعل
I just arrived
وصلت للتو
I have a drink I always order from them Do you want to order it too?
لدي مشروب أطلبه منهم دائمًا هل تريد أن تطلبه أيضًا؟
Yes
نعم
You must have been surprised that I suddenly called you
لابد أنك فوجئت أنني اتصلت بك فجأة
Yes a little
نعم قليلا
Where should I start?
أين يجب أن تبدأ؟
Our university has something called a lifelong learning organization
جامعتنا لديها ما يسمى منظمة التعلم مدى الحياة
It is an organization for the general public
إنها منظمة لعامة الناس
Yes, I know her Lifelong Learning Organization
نعم ، أعرف منظمة التعلم مدى الحياة
We have a place available for an elective class
لدينا مكان متاح للفصل الاختياري
It is not a difficult subject
إنه ليس موضوعًا صعبًا
And I thought of you
وفكرت فيك
To be honest, I want more affiliates in college
لأكون صادقًا ، أريد المزيد من المنتسبين في الكلية
And I'm not actually looking for someone who is very talented
وأنا لا أبحث في الواقع عن شخص موهوب جدًا
Your family's doing great, isn't it?
عائلتك بخير ، أليس كذلك؟
Sorry?
آسف؟
It seems you don't yet know how things work in this world
يبدو أنك لا تعرف حتى الآن كيف تعمل الأشياء في هذا العالم
As you know, many are seeking to take this job
كما تعلم ، يسعى الكثيرون لتولي هذه الوظيفة
So it is not for free
لذلك فهو ليس بالمجان
I see
أرى
Aren't you working in an academy?
الا تعمل في اكاديمية؟
Because you don't have a side to belong to?
لأنه ليس لديك جانب تنتمي إليه؟
This apartment has the best view compared to other apartments in the unit
تتمتع هذه الشقة بأفضل إطلالة مقارنة بالشقق الأخرى في الوحدة
As it overlooks Gyeongbokgung Castle
حيث يطل على قلعة Gyeongbokgung
The apartments above this building are spacious
الشقق فوق هذا المبنى فسيحة
They are not easily available for rent. You are in luck
ليست متاحة بسهولة للإيجار.  كنت في الحظ
Take your time looking around
خذ وقتك في البحث حولك
Why waste your diploma you got from America?
لماذا تضيع شهادتك التي حصلت عليها من أمريكا؟
Being a part of us will give you a sense of belonging
كونك جزءًا منا سيمنحك شعورًا بالانتماء
Your protection under this group is very useful
حمايتك في ظل هذه المجموعة مفيدة للغاية
After all, we are from the same university
بعد كل شيء ، نحن من نفس الجامعة
Can I pay the rent monthly instead of annually?
هل يمكنني دفع الإيجار شهريًا بدلاً من سنوي؟
that's cool
هذا بارد
Anyway, your work at the academy was just a part-time job
على أي حال ، كان عملك في الأكاديمية مجرد وظيفة بدوام جزئي
It's hard to get a lecturer job even with the best degrees
من الصعب الحصول على وظيفة محاضر حتى مع أفضل الدرجات العلمية
I'm worried because it's my first time
أنا قلق لأنها المرة الأولى لي
You know you're going to do well, don't complain too much
أنت تعلم أنك ستفعل جيدًا ، لا تشكو كثيرًا
I will be sent to work in China
سوف يتم إرسالي للعمل في الصين
to China?
إلى الصين؟
China these days is on fire with news
الصين تشتعل في هذه الأيام بالأخبار
That's why they send employees like me who don't have a side to support them
لهذا السبب يرسلون موظفين مثلي ليس لديهم جانب يدعمهم
But they said they will make me a permanent employee when I come back
لكنهم قالوا إنهم سيجعلونني موظفًا دائمًا عندما أعود
For you
لك
You've never been in a situation where you want something but you can't, right?
لم تكن أبدًا في موقف تريد فيه شيئًا ولكنك لا تستطيع ذلك ، أليس كذلك؟
I?
أنا؟
I say this because
أقول هذا بسبب
The director of the academy asked me
سألني مدير الأكاديمية
On what?
على ماذا؟
About if your family was really that rich
حول ما إذا كانت عائلتك غنية حقًا
Honestly, I've always been a bit jealous of you
بصراحة ، لطالما شعرت بالغيرة منك
I envy you so much that you left school
أنا أحسدك كثيرًا لدرجة أنك تركت المدرسة
Without worrying about costs
دون القلق بشأن التكاليف
hello my day
مرحبا يومى
This is my room
هذه غرفتي
You have changed, right?
لقد تغيرت ، أليس كذلك؟
Ah, I'm so tired
آه ، أنا متعب جدًا
I've lived my life really hard
لقد عشت حياتي بصعوبة
but I
لكن أنا
I'm still paying my father's debt
ما زلت أدفع ديون والدي
who was scammed 5 years ago
الذي تم خداعه قبل 5 سنوات
Even if you live hard
حتى لو كنت تعيش بجد
There is no guarantee that I will be rewarded as much as I work
ليس هناك ما يضمن أنني سأكافأ بقدر ما أعمل
But if you mess around a bit,
ولكن إذا عبثت قليلاً ،
I will definitely pay for it
سأدفع بالتأكيد ثمنها
In our organization, we are always short of art students
في منظمتنا ، نحن دائمًا نفتقر إلى طلاب الفنون
That's why I brought a young and beautiful girl to join us
لهذا السبب أحضرت فتاة شابة وجميلة لتنضم إلينا
Have a sense of duty and do your job well
لديك إحساس بالواجب وقم بعملك بشكل جيد
Otherwise, everyone in this room will be in trouble, next year
خلاف ذلك ، سيكون كل شخص في هذه الغرفة في مأزق العام المقبل
Good
جيد
These days, old lecturers are not very popular
في هذه الأيام ، لا يحظى المحاضرون القدامى بشعبية كبيرة
That's why you should have a social standing when you get old
لهذا السبب يجب أن يكون لديك مكانة اجتماعية عندما تكبر
Professor, Doctor, or Lawyer You will finally understand the importance of these titles when you grow up
أستاذ أو دكتور أو محام ستفهم أخيرًا أهمية هذه الألقاب عندما تكبر
Commander
قائد
When you lecture in our organization, others will call you Professor
عندما تُلقي محاضرة في مؤسستنا ، سيتصل بك الآخرون الأستاذ
that's good
هذا جيد
Yes
نعم
Help yourself
ساعد نفسك
Welcome
أهلا وسهلا
I'm going to be teaching the classics reading and reading classes for this class
سأقوم بتدريس فصول القراءة والقراءة الكلاسيكية لهذا الفصل
My name is Lee Anna
اسمي لي آنا
I look forward to teaching you
أنا أتطلع إلى تعليمك
(Callographer Kim Jong-Hui)
(الخطاط كيم جونغ هوي)
It was the calligrapher Kim Jong Hui
كان الخطاط كيم جونغ هوي
He suffers when seeing works that do not meet his standards
يعاني عند رؤية أعمال لا تلبي معاييره
His tongue was always saucy and he used to give barbs
كان لسانه بذيءًا دائمًا وكان يستخدم الانتقادات اللاذعة
He used to see that beautiful things are very important
كان يرى أن الأشياء الجميلة مهمة جدًا
When he sees a job he doesn't like
عندما يرى وظيفة لا تحبه
Doomed to fail
محكوم عليها بالفشل
Or he says it smells bad
أو يقول أن رائحتها كريهة
In fact, he was the first to coin the word "fiasco."
في الواقع ، كان أول من صاغ كلمة "الفشل الذريع".
Maybe we can increase the number of students in the class next semester
ربما يمكننا زيادة عدد الطلاب في الفصل الدراسي القادم
You're so famous, rumors have spread about you
أنت مشهور جدًا ، انتشرت الشائعات عنك
that's not true
هذا ليس صحيحا
I still miss a lot to reach the level of the rest of the teachers
ما زلت أفتقد الكثير للوصول إلى مستوى بقية المعلمين
Miss Lee, won't your family push you to marry?
آنسة لي ، ألا تدفعك عائلتك للزواج؟
indeed
في الواقع
I want to be your marriage broker
أريد أن أكون وسيط زواجك
I'm not ready yet
أنا لست مستعدة بعد
The one I'm suggesting is a little big
الذي أقترحه كبير قليلاً
But you won't regret it
لكنك لن تندم على ذلك
You must have heard of IT Solid before
لابد أنك سمعت عن IT Solid من قبل
She appears a lot in the news IT Solid
تظهر كثيرًا في الأخبار IT Solid
Their stock price has gone up after receiving an investment
ارتفع سعر سهمهم بعد تلقي الاستثمار
The president of the company is an acquaintance of mine from my hometown
رئيس الشركة هو أحد معارفي من مسقط رأسي
He is looking for a girl to marry
إنه يبحث عن فتاة ليتزوجها
Welcome
أهلا وسهلا
nice to meet you
سعيد بلقائك
I've heard a lot about you from Professor Kim
لقد سمعت الكثير عنك من الأستاذ كيم
I didn't know you were a famous person until the professor told me that
لم أكن أعرف أنك شخص مشهور حتى أخبرني الأستاذ بذلك
not at all
لا على الاطلاق
I think the media has been curious about me lately
أعتقد أن وسائل الإعلام كانت تشعر بالفضول تجاهي مؤخرًا
I heard you studied art in America
سمعت أنك درست الفن في أمريكا
OK
نعم
When we built the company building
عندما بنينا مبنى الشركة
I have taken a lot of attention to decorating this hall where we are currently sitting
لقد اهتممت كثيرًا بتزيين هذه القاعة التي نجلس فيها حاليًا
If you notice the pieces in place
إذا لاحظت القطع في مكانها
You will see that each one is very carefully selected
سترى أن كل واحد تم اختياره بعناية فائقة
What do you think of the place?
ما رأيك في المكان؟
Do you like my style?
هل تحب أسلوبي؟
Please rate the place from your artistic point of view
يرجى تقييم المكان من وجهة نظرك الفنية
I feel shy
أشعر بالخجل
I'm not sure
لست واثق
It's hard to get a special flair or sharp look quickly
من الصعب الحصول على مظهر خاص أو حاد بسرعة
But when your taste becomes fine, it's hard to lower your standards
ولكن عندما يصبح ذوقك جيدًا ، فمن الصعب أن تخفض معاييرك
Why are all the seats here?
لماذا كل المقاعد هنا؟
counterfeit goods?
السلع المقلدة؟
How did you know that?
كبف عرفت ذلك؟
I
أنا
I know a little about furniture
أعرف القليل عن الأثاث
My God
ربي
I will be frank with you
سأكون صريحا معك
I'm in no hurry to get married
أنا لست في عجلة من أمري للزواج
Can we meet only three times?
هل يمكننا أن نلتقي ثلاث مرات فقط؟
I will accept your decision then
سأقبل قرارك بعد ذلك
I'm not sure
لست واثق
- Senpai - Yes
- Senpai - نعم
Do you know Choi Ji Hoon from IT Solid
هل تعرف تشوي جي هون من IT Solid
Of course I know him, he's famous
بالطبع أنا أعرفه ، إنه مشهور
Self-made man with great leadership
رجل عصامي مع قيادة عظيمة
In the past year he has appeared in several interviews and their stock has gone up a lot
في العام الماضي ظهر في العديد من المقابلات وارتفع مخزونهم كثيرًا
Why do you ask?
لماذا تسأل؟
Will you enter the world of stocks?
هل ستدخل عالم الأسهم؟
He's a great person
إنه شخص رائع
But it is said that the rich in IT can be dangerous
لكن يقال إن الأثرياء بتكنولوجيا المعلومات يمكن أن يكونوا خطرين
I will postpone his sentence
سأؤجل عقوبته
He was poor before
كان فقيرا من قبل
And as I heard he has a complex about his educational background
وكما سمعت لديه عقدة حول خلفيته التعليمية
What was it called? Is it a lifelong learning organization?
ما كان يسمى؟  هل هي منظمة التعلم مدى الحياة؟
It is said that he takes lessons there at the highest level
يقال إنه يأخذ دروسًا هناك على أعلى مستوى
Let's take a break and drink this
لنأخذ استراحة ونشرب هذا
it is delicious
انه لذيذ
It's late, why are you still awake?
الوقت متأخر ، لماذا مازلت مستيقظا؟
I woke up because of a dream
استيقظت بسبب حلم
Drink this, then sleep
اشرب هذا ثم نم
Are you leaving again?
هل سترحل مرة أخرى؟
what do you mean?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
If you drink this, you will leave for America
إذا شربت هذا ، فسوف تغادر إلى أمريكا
that's not true
هذا ليس صحيحا
I will not leave
أنا لن أغادر
I saw you in my dream a while ago
رأيتك في حلمي منذ فترة
What kind of dream was it?
أي نوع من الحلم كان ذلك؟
I turned into a deer and I was looking at you from afar
تحولت إلى غزال وكنت أنظر إليك من بعيد
Yumi, why were you sad?
يومي ، لماذا كنت حزينة؟
Were you sad in the dream?
هل كنت حزينا في الحلم؟
Yes, and I cried a lot
نعم ، وبكيت كثيرًا
Help yourself
ساعد نفسك
I will not leave anywhere
لن أغادر في أي مكان
But mom
لكن أمي
I will get married
أنا سوف أتزوج
I have no regrets, even if I die now
لا أشعر بأي ندم ، حتى لو مت الآن
Our daughter is very calm
ابنتنا هادئة جدا
So we didn't find out until much later
لذلك لم نكتشف ذلك إلا في وقت لاحق
We didn't even know she had a boyfriend
لم نكن نعرف حتى أن لديها صديقًا
We are thinking of having a big wedding
نحن نفكر في إقامة حفل زفاف كبير
I've learned a lot since I became a member of Tongyeong Council
لقد تعلمت الكثير منذ أن أصبحت عضوًا في مجلس Tongyeong
Thinking of making it big to what extent?
التفكير في جعلها كبيرة إلى أي مدى؟
do not worry
لا تقلق
We will take care of all the equipment
سوف نعتني بجميع المعدات
I am grateful for your consideration
أنا ممتن للنظر
But I can't do nothing
لكن لا يمكنني فعل أي شيء
What are you saying?
ماذا تقول؟
Don't we all worry
لا تقلق جميعنا
About wasting money on the wedding?
حول إضاعة المال على الزفاف؟
Yes that's right
نعم هذا صحيح
We can spend money and hire some people for that too
يمكننا إنفاق الأموال وتوظيف بعض الأشخاص لذلك أيضًا
My God
ربي
How can we return this favor to you?
كيف نرد لك هذه الخدمة؟
I only want one thing
انا اريد شيء واحد فقط
I want a Mercedes-Benz as a gift from my daughter-in-law
أريد سيارة مرسيدس بنز كهدية من زوجة ابني
And this will suffice me
وهذا سوف يكفيني
Not because I want to ride it
ليس لأنني أريد ركوبها
But the fact that it was my daughter-in-law who brought it to me, is what matters
لكن حقيقة أن زوجة ابني هي التي جلبتها لي ، هو ما يهم
naturally
بطبيعة الحال
my dear son
ابني العزيز
Since he was 20 he has only eaten ramen
منذ أن كان في العشرين من عمره ، لم يأكل سوى الرامين
And he worked in selling home subscription accounts to support me
وعمل في بيع حسابات الاشتراك المنزلي لدعمي
He even saved our house that was about to be pawned
حتى أنه أنقذ منزلنا الذي كان على وشك الرهن
Isn't that
أليس كذلك
illegal?
غير شرعي؟
You must not know much because you were outside
يجب ألا تعرف الكثير لأنك كنت بالخارج
You can't make money if you follow all the laws
لا يمكنك كسب المال إذا اتبعت جميع القوانين
You must have waited so long
لا بد أنك انتظرت طويلا
There is nothing wrong
لا يوجد شيء خاطئ
When the wedding ends
عندما ينتهي العرس
My husband and I will take you to the airport
سنأخذك أنا وزوجي إلى المطار
If you want to pass through the crossing gate
إذا كنت تريد المرور عبر بوابة العبور
You should at least travel to a nearby place like Japan
يجب أن تسافر على الأقل إلى مكان قريب مثل اليابان
What? Japan?
ماذا؟  اليابان؟
And also for the wedding
وكذلك لحفل الزفاف
I wish you put more effort into your clothes and hair than today
أتمنى أن تبذل مجهودًا أكبر في ملابسك وشعرك أكثر من اليوم
Why?
لماذا ا؟
Don't like our look?
لا تحب مظهرنا؟
Yes
نعم
When I judge a person's physical condition
عندما أحكم على حالة الشخص الجسدية
I focus on his shoes and his hair
أركز على حذائه وشعره
officially announced
يعلن رسميا
That this marriage went smoothly
أن هذا الزواج سار بسلاسة
And I declare them before you husband and wife
وأعلنها أمامك زوج وزوجة
The new couple's journey will now begin
ستبدأ رحلة الزوجين الجديدين الآن
Bride and groom, move!
العروس والعريس ، تحرك!
What an amazing wedding
يا له من حفل زفاف مذهل
It's true that they didn't even accept any gifts
صحيح أنهم لم يقبلوا أي هدايا
Oh how beautiful they are
كم هم جميلون
Let the parents come
دع الآباء يأتون
Look at the camera
ينظر للكاميرا
one two Three
واحد اثنين ثلاثة
one moment please
لحظة واحدة من فضلك
I am sorry
أنا آسف
Min Jae, come here
مين جاي ، تعال هنا
Min Jae, take a picture with us
مين جاي ، التقط صورة معنا
who is this?
من هذا؟
He's my uncle's grandson named Choi Min Jae
إنه حفيد عمي المسمى تشوي مين جاي
Hello Maine Jay
مرحبا مين جاي
It's a hyacinth flower
إنها زهرة صفير
It grows in the Balkans and Turkey
ينمو في البلقان وتركيا
It grows in the fall
ينمو في الخريف
It has a bulbous rind
لها قشرة منتفخة
what do you say?
ماذا تقول؟
Maine Jay, that's enough
مين جاي ، هذا يكفي
I'll take a picture
سآخذ صورة
Look at the photographer
انظر إلى المصور
Please stand straight
الرجاء الوقوف بشكل مستقيم
one two Three
واحد اثنين ثلاثة
My God
ربي
Professor Lee, the picture is so beautiful
البروفيسور لي ، الصورة جميلة جدا
Roll it up again and put it in that room
قم بلفها مرة أخرى وضعها في تلك الغرفة
Why?
لماذا ا؟
Won't you hang it up?
ألن تقوم بتعليقه؟
Who puts up such cliched things these days?
من الذي يضع مثل هذه الأشياء المبتذلة هذه الأيام؟
I'm going out
أنا ذاهب للخارج
Good
جيد
Goodbye
مع السلامة
The door will open
الباب سيفتح
The door will be closed
سيُغلق الباب
You really...
أنت حقا...
Since you are in our university, why didn't you come to visit me earlier
بما أنك في جامعتنا ، فلماذا لم تأت لزيارتي سابقًا
Makes me feel apart
يجعلني أشعر بالوحدة
I didn't visit you because I knew you'd act like that
لم أزورك لأنني كنت أعرف أنك ستتصرفين هكذا
I stopped him from visiting you for fear of disturbing you
لقد منعته من زيارتك خوفا من إزعاجك
What do you mean by annoyance?
ماذا تقصد بالانزعاج؟
The Dean, your husband, and I are all like one family
أنا والعميد وزوجك كلنا مثل عائلة واحدة
Tongyeong family
عائلة تونغيونغ
This is correct
هذا صحيح
Tongyeong is part of Gyeongsang Province, right?
إن Tongyeong جزء من مقاطعة Gyeongsang ، أليس كذلك؟
I was born in Tongyeong
لقد ولدت في Tongyeong
But I grew up in Ganseong, Jeolla Province
لكني نشأت في جانسيونج بمقاطعة جولا
I see
أرى
Excuse me for a moment
إسمح لي لحظة
It's an urgent call, I'll answer it and come quickly
إنها مكالمة عاجلة ، سأرد عليها وسأعود بسرعة
New Haven?
ملاذ جديد؟
What was the name of that famous pizza shop?
ما هو اسم محل البيتزا الشهير؟
Do you mean Frank Pepe?
هل تقصد فرانك بيبي؟
Right, that's what I mean
صحيح ، هذا ما أعنيه
There was also a garden next to it
كان هناك أيضا حديقة بجانبه
Yes
نعم
It's in front of Worcester Square
إنه أمام Worcester Square
I went there 20 years ago
ذهبت إلى هناك قبل 20 عامًا
But I couldn't forget that shop's pizza
لكنني لم أستطع أن أنسى بيتزا هذا المحل
Right, memories about food
حسناً ، ذكريات عن الطعام
can be fixed
يمكن إصلاحه
I've heard a lot about you
لقد سمعت الكثير عنك
Looks like you're the only one keeping the organization going
يبدو أنك الشخص الوحيد الذي يحافظ على استمرار عمل المنظمة
what are you talking about? this is not true
ما الذي تتحدث عنه؟  هذا ليس صحيحا
Someone as capable as you shouldn't be in that place
شخص قادر كما لا يجب أن يكون في ذلك المكان
Thank you hyungnim
شكرا لك هيونغنيم
He has a sharp look at people
لديه نظرة فاحصة على الناس
Tell the dean to come here
أخبر العميد أن يأتي إلى هنا
Good
جيد
- Right, what about you? - yes
- صحيح ، ماذا عنك؟  - نعم
What news of your candidacy?
ما اخبار ترشيحك؟
It's hard
من الصعب
I am new in this field and I have no connections
أنا جديد في هذا المجال وليس لدي أي اتصالات
Therefore, it is not easy
لذلك ، ليس من السهل
Right, this party is a bit difficult
صحيح ، هذه الحفلة صعبة بعض الشيء
They don't want to accept anything new
لا يريدون قبول أي شيء جديد
What a retarded old man
يا له من رجل عجوز متخلف
Welcome
أهلا وسهلا
I am the professor of Asian Art History for this semester
أنا أستاذ تاريخ الفن الآسيوي في هذا الفصل الدراسي
My name is Lee Anna
اسمي لي آنا
It's my first time studying for university students
إنها المرة الأولى التي أدرس فيها لطلاب الجامعة
That's why I'm so nervous
لهذا أنا متوتر للغاية
I look forward to teaching you
أنا أتطلع إلى تعليمك
She's a graduate of our university and it's her first time attending a meeting like this
إنها خريجة جامعتنا وهذه هي المرة الأولى التي تحضر فيها اجتماعًا كهذا
My colleague Anna
زميلي آنا
Wow, you are my legend Anna?
واو ، أنت أسطورتي آنا؟
Why did you attend the meeting all of a sudden?
لماذا حضرت الاجتماع فجأة؟
People will only talk about it badly
سيتحدث الناس عنها بشكل سيء فقط
what is wrong with you?
ما بكم؟
She's your colleague, it's good to get to know each other
إنها زميلتك ، من الجيد التعرف على بعضكما البعض
Are you close to her?
هل انت قريب منها؟
Yes, I've known her for a while
نعم ، لقد عرفتها منذ فترة
She's as beautiful as the rumors say
إنها جميلة كما تقول الشائعات
is not it?
أليس كذلك؟
She should not study with such a face, she should have fun
لا ينبغي لها أن تدرس بهذا الوجه ، بل يجب أن تستمتع
I've heard a lot about you from Professor Yoon
لقد سمعت الكثير عنك من الأستاذ يون
- You should have come before. - Right
- كان يجب أن تأتي من قبل.  - الصحيح
It's tuna stomach from Spain
إنها معدة التونة من أسبانيا
my husband? He's very busy and I don't see him often
زوجي؟  إنه مشغول للغاية ولا أراه كثيرًا
I don't know much but it looks like he's not going well
لا أعرف الكثير ولكن يبدو أنه لا يسير على ما يرام
naturally
بطبيعة الحال
There are a lot of variables when it comes to politics
هناك الكثير من المتغيرات عندما يتعلق الأمر بالسياسة
It's very stressful work
إنه عمل مرهق للغاية
feel
يشعر
He's a bit obsessed with working out
إنه مهووس قليلاً بالتمرين
I know what you mean
أنا أعرف ماذا تقصد
Your husband has a great desire to be recognized by others
زوجك لديه رغبة كبيرة في أن يتعرف عليه الآخرون
But people are always like that
لكن الناس دائما هكذا
If they have a lot of money
إذا كان لديهم الكثير من المال
They start greed for fame
يبدأون الجشع في الشهرة
People around him are pushing him forward and cheering him on that's why he seems excited
يدفعه الأشخاص من حوله إلى الأمام ويهتفون له لهذا السبب يبدو متحمسًا
And once it really arrives, their reactions become lukewarm
وبمجرد وصوله حقًا ، تصبح ردود أفعالهم فاترة
It's always like that
دائما هكذا
This is not easy
هذا ليس سهلا
to be frank
لأكون صريحا
I wish he didn't get into politics
أتمنى لو لم يدخل السياسة
I don't like to reveal my private life to the public, it makes me feel a burden
لا أحب الكشف عن حياتي الخاصة للجمهور ، فهذا يجعلني أشعر بالعبء
naturally
بطبيعة الحال
This is annoying
هذا مزعج
Maybe it will stop soon, right?
ربما ستتوقف قريبًا ، أليس كذلك؟
A dessert dish consisting of matcha ice cream from Kyoto
طبق حلوى يتكون من آيس كريم ماتشا من كيوتو
(640 thousand won)
(640 ألف وون)
One meal costs 300,000 won
الوجبة الواحدة تكلف 300000 وون
I'm sorry I ate something so expensive
أنا آسف لأني أكلت شيئًا باهظ الثمن
If you say something like that, I will be disappointed
إذا قلت شيئًا من هذا القبيل ، فسوف أصاب بخيبة أمل
What's the best thing about being rich?
ما هو أفضل شيء في كونك ثريًا؟
be honest
كن صادقا
Not hearing others bemoan the loss of money
عدم سماع الآخرين يتحسرون على خسارة المال
OK
نعم
you are right
أنت محق
because I
لأنني
I feel like no one is worth wasting my money on
أشعر أنه لا أحد يستحق إهدار أموالي
Every day I regret
كل يوم يؤسفني
I regret wasting money for today too
أنا آسف لإضاعة المال لهذا اليوم أيضًا
It's delicious
إنه لذيذ
We have expanded our fields
لقد قمنا بتوسيع مجالاتنا
I am very happy to give this opportunity to students with special needs
أنا سعيد جدًا لإعطاء هذه الفرصة للطلاب ذوي الاحتياجات الخاصة
I will always support your dreams and hopes
سأدعم دائما أحلامك وآمالك
I will continue to be by your side in the future
سأظل بجانبك في المستقبل
Hearty congratulations on your scholarship
تهانينا القلبية على منحتك الدراسية
This was a congratulatory message from our sponsor IT Solid
كانت هذه رسالة تهنئة من الراعي IT Solid
Chief
رئيس
Sign language interpreter confused by time
مترجم لغة الإشارة مرتبك بمرور الوقت
He's on his way now but apparently...
إنه في طريقه الآن ولكن على ما يبدو ...
Why aren't things organized properly?
لماذا لا يتم تنظيم الأشياء بشكل صحيح؟
Where is the mother of this child?
أين والدة هذا الطفل؟
She's been out for a while but she hasn't been answering her phone in a while
لقد خرجت لفترة من الوقت لكنها لم ترد على هاتفها منذ فترة
Should we change the order?
هل يجب علينا تغيير الترتيب؟
Yes, we can postpone that to the end
نعم ، يمكننا تأجيل ذلك حتى النهاية
Excuse me
اعذرني
Do you need a sign language interpreter?
هل تحتاج إلى مترجم لغة إشارة؟
Yes, she is deaf and dumb, can you do it?
نعم ، إنها صماء وبكم ، هل يمكنك فعل ذلك؟
from this way
من هذا الطريق
You must be confused by the misunderstanding that happened
يجب أن تكون مرتبكًا بسبب سوء الفهم الذي حدث
She can go now
يمكنها الذهاب الآن
The following paragraph is a farewell letter from scholarship student Lee Jin Young
الفقرة التالية هي رسالة وداع من طالب المنحة Lee Jin Young
There is nothing wrong
لا يوجد شيء خاطئ
Even if you make a mistake, no one but me will know
حتى لو أخطأت ، فلن يعرف أحد سواي
look at me
انظر إليَّ
You fools for not knowing sign language
أنتم حمقى لأنكم لا تعرفون لغة الإشارة
idiots
أغبياء
I'm Lee Jin Young and I've been chosen
أنا Lee Jin Young وقد تم اختياري
To get a scholarship as a talented art student
للحصول على منحة دراسية كطالب موهوب في الفنون
It is true that I can neither hear nor speak
صحيح أنني لا أستطيع أن أسمع ولا أتكلم
But when I draw
لكن عندما أرسم
Become able to communicate with everything in the world
كن قادرًا على التواصل مع كل شيء في العالم
Thank you for giving me such a precious opportunity to make my dreams come true
أشكركم على إعطائي هذه الفرصة الثمينة لتحقيق أحلامي
Choi Ji Hoon of the Democratic Republican Party is getting a lot of attention
تشوي جي هون من الحزب الجمهوري الديمقراطي يحظى باهتمام كبير
His domestic ratings were low
كانت تقييماته المحلية منخفضة
But the public loved him and he became very popular
لكن الجمهور أحبه وأصبح يتمتع بشعبية كبيرة
From now on we expect the competition to be fierce
من الآن فصاعدًا نتوقع أن تكون المنافسة شرسة
The door will open
الباب سيفتح
he arrived
هو وصل
The door will be closed
سيُغلق الباب
This is you, right? daily
هذا انت صحيح؟  اليومي